<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-11-30T10:20:21-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Postal Marines</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">A Decade of Decadent Shaving</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/posts/a-decade-of-shaving" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Decade of Decadent Shaving" /><published>2017-06-17T13:42:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-06-17T13:42:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/posts/a-decade-of-shaving</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/posts/a-decade-of-shaving">&lt;p&gt;After reading a “modern razor” advertising disguised as a blog post, I realized I have had a decade of shaving the “old-fashioned way.” My shaving experience costs me about 45 cents per week including razor blades, shaving soap and after shave—saving $70-200 each year and enjoying an excellent shaving experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been shaving over thirty years. I started with the twin-blade handle razors common in the 1980s with the cartridge refill. Even after I made it out of acne, I found I still had face bump challenges. After a decade in the Army, I realized most of those bumps were caused by ingrown hairs. The shave was too close.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:lifespan&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:lifespan&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In September 2007, I bought a &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2V7vWnP&quot;&gt;Merkur Heavy Duty Razor&lt;/a&gt;. With a cheap set of blades and a devil-may-care attitude, I re-learned how to shave using a much sharper blade. The shaving bumps all but disappeared. The shaves were close enough, but not too close. I was in shaving heaven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a while, I bought the generic safety razor blades at the drug store. This cost me 25-50 cents per week in blades. By the first year, the money I saved in cheaper blades paid for the handle, which cost me $34. Not satisfied with just the razor, I bought the full kit: &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2smqCiH&quot;&gt;shaving soap&lt;/a&gt;, a bowl and brush. I pay about $10 per year in soap now, or 19 cents per week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By 2013, I learned that not all safety-razor blades are created equal. I experimented with a sample pack and suffered through some bad shaves to get to some enjoyable ones. In 2014, I found an article that recommended blades based on blade sharpness and smoothness.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:website&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:website&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; From that article I found a better blade for my face. In September 2014 I bought a box of 100 blades for $12 that &lt;em&gt;I am still using over 143 weeks later&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:usage&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:usage&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; This means I am now paying eight cents a week in blades to shave on average. I spend another $8 per-year for after shave, or 15 cents per week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combined, I am paying 45 cents weekly to keep a clean shaved. This is a far cry from the Gillette Fusion ($4/blade), the Mach3 ($2/blade) or the original blades I bought (now $1.50/blade via discount). Those blades last a week on my beard. This means I have an outstanding shave for (keeping the soap and aftershave the same):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ben’s Safety-Razor - $23.50 per year&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Twin-Blade Cartridge - $96.20 per year (4x more)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mach3 - $122.20 per year (5x more)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gillette Fusion - $226.20 per year (9x more)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why am I boasting about a cheap shave? I’d like to think of this as a rant against modernity. In 1975, Saturday Night Live parodied the twin-blade cartridge with a three-blade saying: “The Triple-Trac. Because you’ll believe anything,” and followed up with a 14-blade parody in 2000. The blade proliferation has become a mockery. I’m glad there’s a movement that goes back to the beginning. Perhaps I should take the next step and go straight razor?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:lifespan&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;For comparison’s sake, this article assumes a blade lasts a full week. The old twin-blade cartridge lasted me about five days. The current blades tend to last about two weeks, but in the early days I tossed them after each week out of habit. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:lifespan&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:website&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The author has since reworked his site and the original article is gone. It is also not retrievable on Archive. Providentially, I made a copy on Evernote. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:website&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:usage&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Current usage suggests I will need new blades this Fall. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:usage&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Ben Wilson</name></author><category term="life hacks" /><category term="Bad advice" /><summary type="html">After reading a “modern razor” advertising disguised as a blog post, I realized I have had a decade of shaving the “old-fashioned way.” My shaving experience costs me about 45 cents per week including razor blades, shaving soap and after shave—saving $70-200 each year and enjoying an excellent shaving experience.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Murder on Guna Prime</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/posts/murder-on-guna-prime" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Murder on Guna Prime" /><published>2016-03-16T13:51:07-04:00</published><updated>2016-03-16T13:51:07-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/posts/murder-on-guna-prime</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/posts/murder-on-guna-prime">&lt;p&gt;Bophendze felt nauseous not long after they landed on Guna Prime. “Angel, how long does it take to contract a local disease?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I feel like I’m going to puke.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Angel laughed and slapped him on the back. “Welcome to the surface, Marine. You’ve been in space long enough that you’ve adjusted to artifical gravity. This is real gravity.” Angel then made a series of short hops in place. “We should only be here a few cycles, so roam around a bit but come back.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bophendze walked out of the hangar and into the sun. It blinded him briefly. His eyes teared. After he adjusted, he breathed deeply natural air and wished he never had to return to space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He strolled through the garrison where they landed. He saw the open parade grounds, about two acres in area. He looked around the grounds, amazed at the green. It was a color he did not realize he had missed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Gunan sun dropped behind the distant trees as it started to set. He felt some peace because of the relative openness of the garrison, and because Smee managed to remain silent. Bophendze felt alone with his thoughts. He decided to head over to the canteen, to see what relaxation meant to a marine on planet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once inside, he felt more relaxed. The canteen was much darker inside than out. It took Bophendze a few minutes for his eyes to adjust. Once they did, he noticed that the windows were shrouded in blackout cloth. &lt;em&gt;Why waste the effort to blackout the building when the Gunans probably know where it is.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bophendze bought a drink at the bar. Sipping his drink, he drifted through each of the canteen’s rooms. He finally settled on a room where they were playing cards. Four sat around one table, looking very intense as they did. Each had varying piles of chips scattered about. The one with his back to the wall had the largest pile. Bophendze watched the four play for several beats, sipping his drink. He had no idea what they were playing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$- It's called Batalo, or Militado, depending on which part of the Imperium 
you hail from. You should play.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;No way. You see the chips? They’re gambling. I don’t know the first thing about Batulo, so they’d fleece me. There’s no way I’m going to risk what little I have on chance.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$- It's Batalo, Puppet, not Batulo. Batulo is the Keicahn word for something 
inappropriate you do with your sister. Batalo's either played with one or two decks.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bophendze watched the game closely as Smee explained the rules. Over the next few beats, a few turns were played. As they were, Smee superimposed the rules in Bophendze’s vision. He felt like he was starting to understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$- It's not nearly as much chance as strategy. The other players know most of what cards you have. It's more important to play the player and not the cards. See the one with his back to the wall? Watch how he looks at the other players when the cards are dealt. He has already figured out how most of them are going to play.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What do you think his chances are?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$- Thirteen percent based on the cards alone. But watch him win anyway. If you sat down at this table, I promise you that you can walk away much better off than you started.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bophendze watched the hand play out. Players laid out number cards, canting them to draw what Smee described as potency, then used face cards to attack the other’s hands. In the end it came down to two players—one being the one with his back to the wall. Based on what was on the table, he was about to lose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You want to give up, Keius? You know that I’m going to win. Want to divide the pot instead?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Don’t bluff, Sablaroki. You know I have you against the wall. Well? Are you going to lay down your next chip and buy into your doom?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Keius, Everytime you thought I was bluffing, I’ve beaten you. So, go ahead, call my bluff so I can win this hand quickly. Don’t waste my time debating.” Sablaroki made a show of counting Keius’ remaining chips—four. He picked up four of his own chips and placed them in the pot. “Are you that certain? Willing to put in your last chips?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keius hesitated. He looked at his cards then at Sablaroki’s. “Fold.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$- See? I told you. He's in their heads now. No way he can't win this table.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What’s to say he doesn’t get into my head?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$- You amaze me with your obtuseness. I'm here. It's not like you're playing by yourself. You might not be able to read his facial ticks, but in the time we've been here I've picked up on his cues. All you have to do is follow my lead. I know the percentages and the game. Since we see all the cards as they're being selected we'll know all but two of what he has. This is a sucker's game.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That’s cheating.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$- If you're not cheating you're not trying, eitehr in this game or in life. Come on. This will be fun. Just play a few hands and make a few dozen quid and we can get out of here.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bophendze weighed the options in his mind. Fine, but if I end up losing my shirt you won’t hear the end of it. “Mind if I join in?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sablaroki had finished sliding the pot to his side. He looked up and eyed Bophendze with suspicion. Then he glanced at the other players.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sure, if you don’t mind him taking all your money.” Keius rose out of his chair. Bophendze noticed Keius was only a little older than he was. “Maybe you’ll have a better chance of beating him than we have.” He turned to the table. “Sablaroki, if you weren’t my friend I’d beat you until you explained how you were cheating.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bophendze took a seat at the table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Twenty quid is minimum to buy in,” Sablaroki said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bophendze looked in his wallet and pulled out a card. “I’ve got thirty on this card. How about we just take twenty off of it? Then I’ll have some money just in case you do clean me out.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sablaroki reached over for the card and pulled out a slate. He tapped a few keys, then slid the card before handing it back. Bophendze looked at the card’s display to confirm that it still had ten quid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He sat down as Sablaroki handed some chips over. “We’re only basic Batalo here. Nothing fancy, and no off-world rules.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Fine. Nothing fancy or foreign. Got it.” &lt;em&gt;Except, I don’t get it. I barely know how to play the game.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$- Don't worry. How about we leave after I earn you forty quid?&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Suits me, or if I lose it all.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sablaroki dealt out the cards. Bophendze picked up each card as it was dealt. He looked at the cards unsure what to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smee posted “17 percent” in Bophendze’s vision with the heading: “victory.” Smee then highlighted the card he wanted Bophendze to keep. It was the Ace of Space, which Smee captioned as the “Hipnoto Fantomo.” As the cards passed around, Smee steadily built a deck for Bophendze, and the percentage of victory that Smee displayed in Bophendze’s vision increased.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$- We'll make a point of losing the first hand quickly. In the second hand we'll bet low and barely pull it out.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fold? I thought you said you were going to help me win.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$- I am, Puppet. But you can't win on your first hand. It will piss them off. Judging by the other player's looks, the player to your right has a hand he'll run all the way. We can help bolster his confidence now so we can strip him clean later.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This sounds a little shady.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$- And being a marine isn't? You're supposedly trained to kill people.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Only if they deserve it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$- A man sitting at a card game is just as deserving being beaten as an  adversary does at being killed. He chose to be a combatant. All we're doing is teaching him the consequences of his actions in a way that earns you more drinking money.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fair enough.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time the betting got around to Bophendze, it was already two quid. He added his one quid. The player to his left folded immediately. Bophendze barely caught the smirk on Sablaroki’s face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Does he think he’s got this?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$- He does, but I'm pretty sure he's going to lose this hand.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sablaroki raised Bophendze’s bet to a full five quid. The player to Bophendze’s right called the bet and made his play with a face card/creature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Too much for me on the first hand. I’m out.” Bophendze tossed his cards down.
Sablaroki swallowed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$- He was expecting you to go another round because of your confidence in the hand, then he was probably going to raise the other player into folding. As the play continued, Sablaroki's position steadily worsened.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The player to Bophendze’s right smiled as he raked in the chips. “Still in the game.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next round of cards ended quickly for Bophendze as he had nothing worthy of buying into. The cards were passed to Bophendze to deal. He shuffled the cards a couple times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$- Don't forget to let me see the cards as you shuffle.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bophendze stopped for a second, wondering if he could get away with it. He decided to give it a shot, and shuffled the deck inverted, looking at the cards as they fanned by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Hold it. I said nothing fancy. You can’t shuffle that way. Pass the cards to the next dealer. Your deal’s done,” Sablaroki said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bophendze held up his hands in defense. “Sorry. Where I come from that’s normal.” He passed the cards over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$- Don't worry. This hand we'll win big.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cards were dealt out, then traded around. Bophendze’s hand looked terrible. &lt;em&gt;I’m going to fold this hand.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$- Don't. Mister overconfident over there is going for a power play. The other two have decent hands, but he'll weed them out. The hand you have will thump him soundly.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You sure?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$- If I don't win this hand for you, you can walk away.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bophendze looked at each of the players. As he did, Smee superimposed cards, as if to tell Bophendze what hand each player was going to play. Bophendze realized the display was based on Smee’s having read the cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$- It doesn't matter that passed the deck. Shuffling is not that random.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sablaroki came out with a four-quid bet. The player next to him folded immediately, despite the display showing he had a pretty formidable hand. Bophendze raised the bet to six quid. The player to the left raised to eight, and Sablaroki raised to 12.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bophendze looked at his cards, planning to fold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$- Stay in. Trust me. Raise him to fourteen.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That’s all I have left.&lt;/em&gt; Bophendze sighed, then pushed in all his chips. “Fourteen.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The player on the left looked at his cards, then at Bophendze’s cards. He seemed to be trying to read the numbers through the opaque backing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bophendze’s card display showed the other player’s hand was fairly strong but would probably not win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Call or fold, make a decision,” Sablaroki sounded defiant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Fold.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Newbie, I’m going to raise you to twenty.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t have that,” Bophendze said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Then you’re going to have to fold.” Sablaroki smirked, wagging his head in a childish way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Better yet.” Bophendze pulled out his card. “I still have ten, so let’s charge off the balance, and I’ll call you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You can’t do that.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why? Is it breaking some fancy or foreign rule? Or are you thinking you can bluff me out?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The player on the left spoke up, “it’s neither. Sablaroki, it’s totally legal and you know it. Afraid he’s going to get a peek at your cards?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sablaroki glowered as he reached for the card. He charged off the six quid Bophendze needed to call. He handed the card and chips to Bophendze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bophendze took the chips and formed a stack in his hand. He held the stack over the bet and slowly dropped each of them. “Call.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sablaroki fumed. He picked up his cards and the two started to play. The round went quickly as Bophendze’s hand was designed to play off of Sablaroki’s weaknesses and destroy his land.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bophendze had two characters and land to supply both, and Sablaroki had no land. The game was effectively over. “Looks like I win. I guess we don’t have to play it out, do we?” He put his hands out to hug the chips and drag them home. As he did, Sablaroki stood up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There’s no way you knew what I had unless you were cheating!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How could I have cheated?” Bophendze felt the blood drain from his face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When you turned the deck over you memorized the order.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How could he have done that?” the player to the left said, laughing. “You’re just a sore loser.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s the only way he could have won that hand. He cheated.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You give me too much credit.” Bophendze returned to scooping the chips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sablaroki looked like he was in no mood to negotiate. “Buddy, leave the chips. Get up and walk away. Or I’ll beat the living breath out of you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bophendze seemed to move on instinct. He grabbed the edge of the table and shot up, flipping the table in the process. Chips and cards flew everywhere. The other players looked shocked, as did Sablaroki and Keius. What’s happening?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$- Shut it.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before Sablaroki could react, Bophendze shoved him against the wall. Rather, Bophendze’s hands shoved Sablaroki. Bophendze had not told them to do anything. He was still trying to understand how he jumped to his feet and acted without thinking. He pulled Sablaroki from the wall and quickly shoved him again. Sablaroki’s head struck the masonry wall from the whiplash maneuver. Bophendze repeated the attack a couple more times. Sablaroki’s head slamming into the wall was loud enough to be heard over the buzz of the canteen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He released Sablaroki, who dropped lifeless to the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other marines sat or stood stunned. After a few breaths, Keius spoke up. “You killed him. You killed my friend.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bophendze was nearly petrified from what had happened. &lt;em&gt;How did I do that.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$- You didn't do it, Puppet. I did. I couldn't wait for you to get a couple of your neurons to meet and consummate a thought. He's not dead, but he'll be in the hospital for a few days and will have a headache for some time after.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The words that came out of Bophendze’s mouth were not his. “He’s not dead, but I won’t let him get away with calling me a cheat.” He waited to see what the other marines would do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keius was angry. “We’re going to let this postie waltz in here, win a big hand and beat one of ours cold?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Keius, you really think we can take on a marine who can do what he just did? I mean, I barely blinked from the time he was sitting until Sablaroki was on the ground. He’s probably an anthorph.” Achos looked up at Bophendze, who was still trying to take in what had just happened. “No offense. I don’t have anything against your kind.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My kind? I’m not an anthorph.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$- They don't know that. Appearances can be deceiving. And to answer the  question you're not asking, I beat him down. He had a baton in his hand he was about to use on you.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bophendze bent down and picked up Sablaroki’s hand. The baton was still collapsed. He pried it out of Sablaroki’s hand. “He was going to use this on me. I’m going to take it, okay?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sure, buddy. Whatever you want,” the one to his left said. “Just give me your card so I can give you your share.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the crazy marine left, Keius went over to Sablaroki’s slumped body. He put his finger to Sablaroki neck. “He’s dead.” Keius started for the door when someone grabbed his arm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Stop,” Achos said.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ben Wilson</name></author><category term="Forbearance" /><summary type="html">Bophendze felt nauseous not long after they landed on Guna Prime. “Angel, how long does it take to contract a local disease?”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fragile Societies, Resilient Citizens</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/posts/fragile-societies-resilient-citizens" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fragile Societies, Resilient Citizens" /><published>2016-02-06T14:53:31-05:00</published><updated>2016-02-06T14:53:31-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/posts/fragile-societies-resilient-citizens</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/posts/fragile-societies-resilient-citizens">&lt;p&gt;I recently had the pleasure of listening to a lecture by the Science Fiction author David Brin. It is amazing how one hour can pack so much. I only wish that I had brought my recorder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brin’s lecture thesis was that advanced society was inherently fragile, and that resilience and thoughtfulness are necessary to mitigate this fragility in times of catastrophe or calamity. I assert that ultimately, that requires that one balance one’s self-interest against the interests of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fragility-and-resilience&quot;&gt;Fragility and Resilience&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Societal Fragility&lt;/strong&gt; comes from diverse sources, including external and internal human threats as well as environmental threats. He included ignorant progressiveness, which is changing society or implementing technology in the interest of progress without a full understanding what the ramifications are. The more advanced a society, the more inherently fragile it becomes. Ignorantly advancing a society leads to not incorporating adequate resilience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Citizen Resilience&lt;/strong&gt; is the buttress, or proof against Societal Fragility. There are two key factors: the citizen’s ability to act and the citizen’s willingness to act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example of &lt;em&gt;ability to act&lt;/em&gt; is a firearm that bridges the time between when the emergency call is made and the police arrive. Or, the possession of residential solar power to offset power loss when there is a regional outage. Or, the ability to dig one’s self out of the snow when the plows are late. The concept of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Individualism&quot;&gt;American Individualism&lt;/a&gt; encourages Citizen Resilience. Ability to act means one has the means to do so, which is having access to relevant technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were two excellent examples of &lt;em&gt;willingness to act&lt;/em&gt;. Hitler under-estimated the American’s willingness to fight when he declared war, thinking we were too decadent. Likewise, the brave sacrifice on &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_Airlines_Flight_93&quot;&gt;United Airlines Flight 93&lt;/a&gt; evidences willingness to act when they gave their lives to prevent greater calamity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brin asserted that Americans have been historically willing to act and still are, contrary to modern propaganda, and rattled off several other notorious examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thoughtfulnessthe-zero--and-positive-sum-societies&quot;&gt;Thoughtfulness:&lt;br /&gt;The Zero- and Positive-Sum Societies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brin described two societies: Zero- and Positive-Sum. The &lt;strong&gt;Zero-Sum Society&lt;/strong&gt; is the ancient Feudal Attractor society where there are a few at the top with the wealth and power to control the many. The &lt;strong&gt;Positive-Sum Society&lt;/strong&gt; is a construct of the Enlightenment, where there are a few very wealthy and a few very poor, but where those who are neither have most of the power. A higher proportion of wealth is shared than is found among the wealthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where the Zero-Sum society is described as a triangle (△), the Positive-Sum Society is described as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lozenge&quot;&gt;lozenge&lt;/a&gt; (◊). The tendency of Zero-Sum is to limit society growth, the result of Positive-Sum is that all eventually rise in status. As a society of the Enlightenment, Americans should encourage Positive-Sum Philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Zero-Sum Philosophy exists whenever a few exercise monopolistic control over a society sub-culture. In the commerce sub-culture, this is where one or two corporations exercise monopolistic control or where government does. Conversely, a thriving small business culture in commerce is more Positive-Sum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brin observed Zero-Sum Philosophy applied in the desire to regulate routine citizen access to &lt;strong&gt;Dangerous Technology&lt;/strong&gt;. He pointed out that with any technology, there are always Good and Bad actors. The &lt;strong&gt;Good:Bad Actor Ratio&lt;/strong&gt; (GBAR) tends to be greater when there is broad access to technology. Undue regulation restricts broad access, which disproportionately impacts the Good Actor. Undue regulation thus reduces the &lt;abbr title=&quot;Good:Bad Actor Ratio&quot;&gt;GBAR&lt;/abbr&gt;, ultimately favoring the Bad Actor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dangerous Technology is a pejorative applied by those seeking to regulate, when in reality a technology is only dangerous when used by Bad Actors. Undue regulation belongs to the Zero-Sum Philosophy and Society. To promote a Positive-Sum Society, Brin encouraged the broad dissemination of technologies, and avoiding the temptation to regulate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-protector-caste-should-be-simultaneously-celebrated-and-controlled&quot;&gt;The Protector Caste Should be Simultaneously Celebrated and Controlled&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Protector Caste&lt;/strong&gt; comprises the military, law enforcement, emergency medical technician, firefighters, some scientists and others—those we rely upon to be vigilant and anticipatory while the rest of us live “normal” lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Brin’s perspective, the Protector Caste should only be powerful enough to handle the routine. During times of calamity and catastrophe, the Protector Caste should only be powerful enough to give the Resilient Citizenry time to mobilize and act. It should never be powerful enough to exercise monopolistic control. The Resilient Citizenry should always have more effective power, because enough Good Actors will balance the Bad and not operate in a way that adversely interferes with another’s interests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In World War 2, our military was small, and only held off long enough for the Resilient Citizen soldier to be trained and applied to action; which explains why the early period for the Americans and the British felt so desperate. We have since tended toward having a military that is capable of acting without engaging the resilient citizen; causing some resentment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;technology-enables-positive-sum-societies&quot;&gt;Technology Enables Positive-Sum Societies.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Electric companies act in their self-interests by restricting broad implementation of residential solar power. They seek regulations under the guise of the danger residential solar poses to the linemen. Conversely, &lt;abbr title=&quot;non-ignorant&quot;&gt;mindful&lt;/abbr&gt; implementation of this technology would safeguard the linemen without the need for constrictive regulation—broad implementation sans endangerment. The result of the Zero-Sum regulation is a brittle electrical infrastructure that could not withstand a catastrophe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some label firearms a dangerous technology and advocate restriction to an &lt;abbr title=&quot;elite at its basest is a chosen few&quot;&gt;elite&lt;/abbr&gt;—the very model of Zero-Sum philosophy at work. Where these regulations are more strictly applied, it has lowered the &lt;abbr title=&quot;Good:Bad Actor Ratio&quot;&gt;GBAR&lt;/abbr&gt;; more criminals per capita have firearms than citizens.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:thought&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:thought&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;
Conversely, when society broke down during the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1992_Los_Angeles_riots#Second_day_.28Thursday.2C_April_30.29&quot;&gt;LA Riots&lt;/a&gt;, private use of firearms were used to resist a riot.
In times of protracted crisis, the broader access to this technology leads to a well-ordered society–a “well-ordered &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Militia&quot;&gt;militia&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:militia&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:militia&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The early Enlightenment thinkers, our Founders, recognized the power of  resilience and hard-coded it into our government. Most of the amendments in the Bill of Rights were enacted to open access to technology and thwart regulation in an effort to foster the Positive-Sum Philosophy belonging to the Enlightenment. Even the Copyright and Patent provisions of the U.S. Constitution were intended to open access and thwart regulation. Having open access to countervailing opinions is Positive-Sum, attempting to regulate or silence one’s opponents is Zero-Sum thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Historically, other technologies were labeled dangerous. At one point, governments restricted presses, which focused propaganda power in the elite.  Some assert that the commercial media similarly concentrates power, where social media and other avenues tend to be more egalitarian. Access to the Bible in the vernacular challenged the Zero-Sum power of the church elite. Amateur Radio exemplifies where there are enough regulations to foster a community needed during emergencies, but over-regulated by limiting access to those in &lt;abbr title=&quot;Home Owner's Associations&quot;&gt;HOA&lt;/abbr&gt;s; whose only harm is an unsightly skyline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brin observed that there are numerous technologies that we tend to no longer consider such; something that an avid player of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Civilization_%28series%29&quot;&gt;Civilization video game series&lt;/a&gt; recognizes. Education (literacy, numeracy, reasoning, rhetoric) is  technology, and one that some consider too regulated by government…and needs to have broader access of means.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;where-zero-sum-thinking-comes-from&quot;&gt;Where Zero-Sum Thinking Comes From&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brin optimistically asserted that Atheism encourages Positive-Sum and that religion is Zero-Sum. However, there are sufficient examples where Atheism has led to very Zero-Sum outcomes. Conversely, the Enlightenment movement emerged and matured in Protestant Christian regions. Yet, there are plenty of Zero-Sum thinkers among Protestants. I believe the true source of this conflict lay not in religion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather, the root is in our natural tendency to have a strong belief (likely unfounded) that one’s interests, opinions and beliefs are superior to another’s, and that &lt;em&gt;they&lt;/em&gt; therefore need to be controlled. This is literally the definition of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/self%E2%80%93righteous&quot;&gt;self-righteousness&lt;/a&gt;. Zero-Sum Philosophy and behavior is self-righteous. Positive-Sum Philosophy is not, because it requires a recognition that other’s interests, opinions and beliefs have equal merit. A tendency to be self-righteous is a part of our human nature, and requires conscientious  effort to overcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When our behavior balances our self-interest and other’s-interest, we are Good Actors and favor Resilience. As a Society, we need Good Actors who have access to the means to act to endure during calamity and catastrophe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:thought&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Here’s an interesting thought experiment. You have three persons. Person A is a model citizen with a gun. Person B is a criminal with a gun who wants to harm Person A. Person C seeks to regulate guns, recognizing that Person B will not surrender their gun. Would Person C therefore be supporting Person B more than Person A? &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:thought&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:militia&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Militia as a legal term is distinct in that it is not compelled to government control, which contrasts the National Guard which is an element of government control. There are no legal repercussions if a citizen chooses not to act in a militia capacity, which is not true of the Guardsman. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:militia&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Ben Wilson</name></author><category term="Brin" /><category term="Resiliency" /><summary type="html">I recently had the pleasure of listening to a lecture by the Science Fiction author David Brin. It is amazing how one hour can pack so much. I only wish that I had brought my recorder.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jonaldy Ammonett</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/posts/jonaldy-ammonett" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jonaldy Ammonett" /><published>2015-08-23T09:42:00-04:00</published><updated>2015-08-23T09:42:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/posts/jonaldy-ammonett</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/posts/jonaldy-ammonett">&lt;p&gt;The Postal Marine Series is set nearly two millenia in the future. When I conceived of the series, I wanted to recognize that human nature is immutable regardless of time. The Invisible Hand still operates. The Postal Marines are there to try to manage it a bit. As I am editing &lt;em&gt;Luctation&lt;/em&gt;, I wanted to chat a bit about the main character: Jonaldy Ammonett.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an earlier article, I mention the &lt;a href=&quot;/postal-marine-series/the-bafiktuy-directive/&quot;&gt;Bafiktuy&lt;/a&gt;, one of the most secretive organizations in the Imperium. This organization thinks &lt;em&gt;it&lt;/em&gt; is the Invisible Hand, while in reality it is more like the hand slipping into your pocket looking for loose change. Admiral Bence in &lt;em&gt;Bellicose&lt;/em&gt; was a senior member, though not a capo. In &lt;em&gt;Lucatation&lt;/em&gt;, we are introduced to Jonaldy Ammonett, a low-ranked somewhat inept operative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some parallels between the two books. Both reveal the earlier careers of young men. Bophendze had to overcome legitimate incompetence, and did so only with Smee. Jonaldy is competent, he just lacks confidence. Through the story, other characters give it to him. He is otherwise a very cautious, and eventually very manipulative man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We run into Jonaldy again in &lt;em&gt;Scintilla&lt;/em&gt;. There, we see him at the height of his ruthlessness. For now, we’ll just have to enjoy the fact that all the great men of society were once little boys wondering how they were going to find their way in a big world.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ben Wilson</name></author><category term="Postal Marines Series" /><category term="Writing Progress" /><summary type="html">The Postal Marine Series is set nearly two millenia in the future. When I conceived of the series, I wanted to recognize that human nature is immutable regardless of time. The Invisible Hand still operates. The Postal Marines are there to try to manage it a bit. As I am editing Luctation, I wanted to chat a bit about the main character: Jonaldy Ammonett.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/luctation.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/luctation.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Breaking the Silence</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/posts/breaking-the-silence" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Breaking the Silence" /><published>2015-04-18T21:04:00-04:00</published><updated>2015-04-18T21:04:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/posts/breaking-the-silence</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/posts/breaking-the-silence">&lt;p&gt;After a few hard months, I’m back in business. I thought it would be appropriate for me to break the silence a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal for this year is to finish &lt;em&gt;Luctation&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Imbroglio&lt;/em&gt;. A stretch goal is to finish plotting the fifth novel in the series &lt;em&gt;Serendipity&lt;/em&gt; or plot the next novel series. The first step is to finish &lt;em&gt;Luctation&lt;/em&gt; by July. However, I did not start the revision until last weekend. The family was out-of-town and I thought I could get some serious revision work done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, I documented my personal approach to writing a series, and updated my business plan. I did get the first chapter edited as I planned. Today I wrapped up chapter two. Depending on what’s going on tomorrow, I might get chapter three done. That will be a full quarter of the book through the second draft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sort of having fun with &lt;em&gt;Luctation&lt;/em&gt; this time. I finished the first draft last August, and did not touch it or read it since. I sat down and re-plotted it in March, with what I thought were some serious changes. As I go through the second draft, I see that the re-plotted &lt;em&gt;Luctation&lt;/em&gt; was there all along. There were inconsistencies in the first draft. By trimming out the inconsistencies in favor of the new plot, the story seems to pull together better. Because of this, I expect the revision will wrap up quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal is to have &lt;em&gt;Luctation&lt;/em&gt; out by July. That is audacious.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ben Wilson</name></author><category term="Writing Progress" /><summary type="html">After a few hard months, I’m back in business. I thought it would be appropriate for me to break the silence a bit.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/3400504522-dcc68458ce-silence.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/3400504522-dcc68458ce-silence.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Inspiration for the Postal Marines</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/posts/inspiration-for-the-postal-marines" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Inspiration for the Postal Marines" /><published>2014-11-16T10:11:39-05:00</published><updated>2014-11-16T10:11:39-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/posts/inspiration-for-the-postal-marines</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/posts/inspiration-for-the-postal-marines">&lt;p&gt;It’s time to share some backstory on how Danel Bophendze was able to join the Postal Marines at sixteen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been to lots of different places and met a lot of peculiar people. In the Postal Marines series, I find some of those more interesting people found their way into shades of characters. I’ve not figured out who Bophendze is yet, but there are a few others where I had somebody in mind. One of those is the scouting couple in &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/books/#imbroglio&quot;&gt;Imbroglio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Danel is an orphan. It’s clear from the early parts of the series he has no idea who his father was. He was raised by his mother until she died when he was sixteen. Part of this series is his learning the richness of his heritage and has to come to terms with it. This is no Harry Potter, however. (Spoiler alert: Bophendze learns more about his heritage in &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/books/#imbroglio&quot;&gt;Imbroglio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Imperial Postal Service has an interesting provision in its recruiting policy. It will recruit as young as sixteen. The young lads are part of an auxiliary. They are paid at recruit rates but are not expected to join the service until they are eighteen. The exception is for orphans. They can ask to join active service immediately. This provides them with room and board an a chance to promote earlier. the Emperor extended this as his benevolence to the orphan who has nobody in the world to care for him. The minimum enlistment period for such a privilege is a decade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea for the auxiliary came from an interaction I had with members of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Queen%27s_Own_Highlanders_%28Seaforth_and_Camerons%29&quot;&gt;the Queen’s Own Highlanders&lt;/a&gt;. The unit has changed since I met them. It has been twenty years, so there’s a good chance some of them are still serving. For a few hours in the early 1990s, I had a chance to get a glimpse into their world, after their tour in North Ireland. Among those was a the different recruiting and retention methods of their unit. It is from my recollection of that encounter that influenced the Imperial Postal Service’s policy to recruit orphans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with recruiting men so young is their emotional and physical disadvantages. In &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/books/#bellicose&quot;&gt;Bellicose&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, Bophendze is still emotionally raw from the loss of his mother. Psychologically, he is ill-adapted to the transitions he is exposed to. It took the pivotal moment of Tannenberg Gate before he could find equilibrium with his new environment.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ben Wilson</name></author><category term="Postal Marines Series" /><summary type="html">It’s time to share some backstory on how Danel Bophendze was able to join the Postal Marines at sixteen.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/bellicose-redo-wallpaper.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/bellicose-redo-wallpaper.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Machines Like Us</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/posts/machines-like-us" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Machines Like Us" /><published>2014-11-02T12:30:06-05:00</published><updated>2014-11-02T12:30:06-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/posts/machines-like-us</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/posts/machines-like-us">&lt;p&gt;Computers will soon become more intelligent than us. Some of the best brains in Silicon Valley are now trying to work out what happens next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least, that’s how the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ft.com/cms/s/2/abc942cc-5fb3-11e4-8c27-00144feabdc0.html&quot;&gt;article at FT Magazine&lt;/a&gt; starts. The article discusses how we are trying to come to grips with the ramifications of having human-intelligent machines and computers. Yes, this has been the staple of Science Fiction for decades. One of my more favorite is &lt;em&gt;Colossus&lt;/em&gt;, a 1970 movie where two sentient computers decided to rule man because he cannot rule himself. Science Fiction as a genre helps us explore the philosophical elements of technology long before it exists. Per the article, now scientists are getting serious about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&quot;/books&quot;&gt;Postal Marine Series&lt;/a&gt;, we get to know Smee. He was one of the last fully sentient, embeddable artificial intelligences made in the Terradoma. The problem with Smee and his peers is an uncanny desire to be in charge. One of the reviews for &lt;em&gt;Bellicose&lt;/em&gt; commented that Smee was far too human in his behavior. That humanity was the critical failure in the Ennui design, the design of those AI. Scientists thought the human nature in the AI could be constrained by the host. Smee proves otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet for some reason, Danel Bophendze is much better at controlling Smee. At least, that’s the way it looks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sentient artificial intelligence forces us to look at our own nature. As the Creator, we cannot help but fear our creature, the AI. Will Smee ultimately dominate Bophendze as he had dominated before? That’s a question for the entire series. So, keep reading.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ben Wilson</name></author><category term="goals" /><summary type="html">Computers will soon become more intelligent than us. Some of the best brains in Silicon Valley are now trying to work out what happens next.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/3318600273-3ef4c48d0a-b-machine.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/3318600273-3ef4c48d0a-b-machine.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Finished Bellicose Draft</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/posts/finished-bellicose-draft" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Finished Bellicose Draft" /><published>2014-01-21T19:21:07-05:00</published><updated>2014-01-21T19:21:07-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/posts/finished-bellicose-draft</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/posts/finished-bellicose-draft">&lt;p&gt;I started Bellicose in 2012, after two other projects were stalled. I slowly worked my way to completion in 2013. After committing to only 500 words per day, I completed the draft on 21 January. You can see my &lt;a href=&quot;/posts-logs/2014-progress&quot;&gt;writing progress&lt;/a&gt; as I continue. My next step is to pick up the &lt;em&gt;Luctation&lt;/em&gt; draft and work it through to completion.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Postal Marines Series" /><category term="Writing Progress" /><summary type="html">I started Bellicose in 2012, after two other projects were stalled. I slowly worked my way to completion in 2013. After committing to only 500 words per day, I completed the draft on 21 January. You can see my writing progress as I continue. My next step is to pick up the Luctation draft and work it through to completion.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/bellicose-redo-wallpaper.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/bellicose-redo-wallpaper.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Work in Progress: Bellicose</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/posts/work-in-progress-bellicose" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Work in Progress: Bellicose" /><published>2012-07-15T15:26:00-04:00</published><updated>2012-07-15T15:26:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/posts/work-in-progress-bellicose</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/posts/work-in-progress-bellicose">&lt;p&gt;I’m finally in pre-production for &lt;em&gt;Bellicose&lt;/em&gt;, the first of the Postal Marine Series. Last Fall, I published &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/books/&quot;&gt;Scintilla&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, which was always meant to be the fourth of a series of five novels. I quickly plotted the second novel &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/books/&quot;&gt;Luctation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, a novel portraying Jonaldy, &lt;em&gt;Scintilla&lt;/em&gt;’s villain as the hero. After grinding out 20,000 words, I felt that something wasn’t quite right. Since then, I’ve been wrestling over how to proceed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past few weeks, I’ve been re-evaluating the series. By taking a step back and looking at the entire series, I was able to get a new perspective. I’ve started plotting &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/books/&quot;&gt;Bellicose&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, which is essentially the creation story of the Postal Marine Series’ major protagonist, Danel Bophendze. Having written the logline, I’m moving to the one-page plot synopsis. Wish me luck!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ben Wilson</name></author><category term="Writing Progress" /><category term="Postal Marines Series" /><summary type="html">I’m finally in pre-production for Bellicose, the first of the Postal Marine Series. Last Fall, I published Scintilla, which was always meant to be the fourth of a series of five novels. I quickly plotted the second novel Luctation, a novel portraying Jonaldy, Scintilla’s villain as the hero. After grinding out 20,000 words, I felt that something wasn’t quite right. Since then, I’ve been wrestling over how to proceed.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/bellicose-redo-wallpaper.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/bellicose-redo-wallpaper.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">When Friends Take a Turn for the Worse</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/posts/when-friends-take-a-turn-for-the-worse" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="When Friends Take a Turn for the Worse" /><published>2011-08-05T14:54:00-04:00</published><updated>2011-08-05T14:54:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/posts/when-friends-take-a-turn-for-the-worse</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/posts/when-friends-take-a-turn-for-the-worse">&lt;p&gt;Have you ever known somebody who turned out to be somebody else? Come to rely on that person, that go-to person, only to find out he had feet of clay? Sometimes that friend was never your friend, they were just setting you up for their advantage. I’m going to talk about a friend who did not betray me, but he let me down because I thought he was better than that. I’ll call him Daniel for anonymity. This is his &lt;em&gt;true&lt;/em&gt; story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He drove down the busy highway with a mix of paranoia and excitement. It had been a while since his last fix, and he needed it now. It did not matter if it was late on a Tuesday night—right before a customer meeting—or that he had to drive 26.2 miles from his house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When he pulled into the apartment complex, the excitement died down. He had not been here before, and the complex was run down. Even at night under the streetlight he could tell that the residents here learned to live with depredation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He stopped  his BMW Z3. While it was an older model it still cost more than any three cars in the parking lot. Would he make it out? Would he score? Without any movement outside, he fought the urge to peel out and just go home. &lt;em&gt;I could at least have left the top up.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just before he gave into panic, he saw movement. It was a young boy trotting toward him from an area of the complex that was unlit. As the boy came to his car, my friend wondered &lt;em&gt;how could a six year-old get into this business?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You got the money?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daniel handed over his cash without a word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boy trotted back into the darkness, oblivious to the nature of the business. Not long after, an older boy—a teenager—walked out of the darkness. His relaxed stroll made Daniel feel a bit more confident that he would get out. Something about the natural gait had a soothing effect. Or, maybe it was the box under the teen’s arm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The teen handed the box to Daniel without a word and walked away. He fought the urge to challenge &lt;em&gt;is it all there?&lt;/em&gt; Instead, he put his car into first and did what he wanted to before—he peeled out. Better to get out of the area before criminal or cop came after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the drive home, Daniel resisted the urge to open the box. He felt foolish for even going, knowing he could have gotten his fix anywhere. But, the prices at that apartment complex were the cheapest around–even online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally in his 3-car garage at his micro-mansion, Daniel let his excitement win. He put the box in his lap and ripped the top off. His eyes gleamed with delight as he saw what he risked his reputation, and his car, for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inside were over a dozen decks of Magic: The Gathering. He would need them for a competition that weekend. Now he had the rest of the week to plan his strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is “Daniel’s” &lt;em&gt;true&lt;/em&gt; story. I know far too many geeks. But, not too unlike the intrigue in &lt;em&gt;Scintilla&lt;/em&gt;, my first Science Fiction novel due out this Summer.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ben Wilson</name></author><category term="Writing" /><category term="Postal Marines Series" /><summary type="html">Have you ever known somebody who turned out to be somebody else? Come to rely on that person, that go-to person, only to find out he had feet of clay? Sometimes that friend was never your friend, they were just setting you up for their advantage. I’m going to talk about a friend who did not betray me, but he let me down because I thought he was better than that. I’ll call him Daniel for anonymity. This is his true story.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/503020765-dd1efcf5fc-friends.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/postal-marines-series/503020765-dd1efcf5fc-friends.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>